Suryakiran Sureshkumar

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/suryakiran-sureshkumar/

Address:

RH-51, Meenakshi Avenue, Kalai Nagar 1st Street, Madurai - 625017.

Phone: +91 9488631223

Email: suryakiranbdsk@gmail.com

Summary

Specialized in Computer Science and Engineering, gained experience in the fields of Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Mobile and Web application development by participating in various hackathons, doing projects related to it in my curriculum as well as having work experience on it.

Education

Thiagarajar College of Engineering - Madurai, India

Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Science and Engineering – 2017 to 2021

Cumulative GPA: 9.11/10

Areas of Interest

• Data Science and Analytics

• Machine Learning and Computer Vision

- Web and Mobile application development
- Cloud Computing

Experience

• Tiger Analytics, Chennai, India

Analyst, Machine Learning Engineering – 09/2021 to Present

- o I am the primary backend developer for a no-code data science platform.
- o I was also the application developer for a project which involved computer vision and machine learning.

Analyst, Data Science - 07/2021 to 08/2021

o I worked on big data technology to improve the performance in the internal framework.

Data Analyst Intern – 02/2021 to 07/2021

O I gained experience in python for data analytics, Excel for handling and visualizing data, python packaging and distributing, docker container deployment.

• National University of Singapore, Singapore

Academic Intern – 06/2019

- o Educational internship on Big Data Analytics using Artificial Neural Networks.
- This program introduced me to Data Analytics, Exploratory Data Analysis, Descriptive Statistical Measures, Python Data Science Libraries, Regression Analysis, Classification, Clustering, Text Mining, Association, Artificial Neural Networks, Convolution Neural Networks, Recurrent Neural Networks.
- O I did Phishing Site Detection as my end project which also got the best project award at the end of the intern.

• Hewlett Packard Enterprise, Singapore

Summer Intern – 06/2019

- o Training on Big data and Hadoop System Administration.
- This introduced me to Big Data and Hadoop, Pseudo Mode, Setting up Cloudera Manager, HDFS Shell commands, Commissioning and Decommissioning, HDFS Quotas, Hadoop Architecture, Kerberos, Knox, MapReduce, Hive, Kafka, Flume.

Skill Highlights

Programming Languages	C, C++, Python, Java
Web Technologies	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP
Database	MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB

Paper Publication

Scene Understanding in Night-Time Using SSAN Dataset - It was published in Springer, Singapore as a part of the National Conference on Computer Vision, Pattern Recognition, Image Processing, and Graphics. **Deep learning framework for component identification** - It was published in International Journal of Information Technology through Springer.

Projects

• Deep Learning Framework for Component Identification

 It is a setup to monitor the assembly line of a manufacturing unit which uses an object detection algorithm to detect, classify and count the various components in the monitored image.

Covid Fight

O This is a mobile application that helps users during the coronavirus pandemic. The features of the app include delivering a live count of cases, a crisis communication chatbot that helps users resolve their doubts regarding the pandemic, a self-diagnosis feature, notifying the users to wash their hands regularly, and giving them immediate access to the distress number.

• Phishing Site Detection

o It is a web application with a chrome extension that detects whether a particular website is phishing or not, using a neural network, by extracting 14 features from the particular site. A comprehensive analysis of the attack will be periodically sent to the cyber department.

Night-time object detection using machine learning

o It is a setup that uses a normal CCTV camera and improves image eliminating unwanted objects and detects required objects at night.

Co-Curricular Activities

- Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2020 & 2021 Certified Associate.
- Received Spoken Tutorial (Program offered by IIT Bombay) certificates for C, C++, Java, PHP, MySQL.
- Completed 4 courses in Google Data Analytics course.
- Selected for Regionals round of Vishwakarma Awards.
- Presented paper in Seventh National Conference on Computer Vision, Pattern Recognition, Image Processing and Graphics for my paper on Night-time object detection using machine learning.
- Presented Paper in International Conference on Current Trends in Advanced Computing on Deep Learning Framework for Component Identification.
- Participated in the Crack the Covid Crisis Hackathon conducted by IBM.
- Won the Best stall of the year for TensorFlow and Theano in FS'tival 2018, an inter-school cultural fest.
- Participated in Smart India Hackathon 2019.
- Participated in a 3-Day workshop conducted by Sirius on React JS Web Application Development.

Leadership Activities

- Placement Representative of Department of Computer Science (Aug 2019 May 2021).
- Co-founder of Placement Club.
- Office bearer of Institution of Engineering and Technology (IET) for Department of Computer Science.
- Mentor at Certatim 2019, a hackathon organized by Computer Science Department.
- Event coordinator in QUEST 2020, an interschool event conducted by Thiagarajar College of Engineering.
- Event coordinator in Tecutsav 2020, a technical symposium conducted by Thiagarajar College of Engineering.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Secured Second Place in the event BizQuiz conducted by Entrepreneurship Development Cell.
- Level 1 award in Grade 3 examination in Theory of music with Distinction by Trinity College London
- Won Second Place in Prove It contest organized as a part of Glitzia 2k18 conducted by Computer Science and Engineering Association, Thiagarajar College of Engineering.
- Secured First Position in Quiz Wizard Contest conducted by Computer Society of India Student Branch, Thiagarajar College of Engineering.